Guide to the Womonwrites Records, 1979-2014 RL.01408
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Womonwrites records
1979-2014
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Womonwrites
RL.01408
3.0 Linear Feet
Womonwrites is an annual conference of lesbian writers. Collection includes anthologies of writings by Womonwriters (conference attendees), conference chronological files, meeting notes, meeting evaluations, and membership lists. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
1875 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is restricted.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Womonwrites Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2010.
Historical Note
Womonwrites is an annual Southeast lesbian writers' conference. It is run entirely by participants who volunteer each year for planning positions. There are no invited speakers, and the only paid staff are the cooks and the child care provider. It offers lesbian identified writers in all stages of development the opportunity to learn, teach, support, critique, and share their work, as well as time to socialize and have fun. The five-day spring conference includes participant-led workshops, affinity groups, open readings, and recreations. The fall conference is much more informal and lasts four days. Womonwrites is an annual conference created by and for the participants that began in 1979.
Collection Overview
Collection includes anthologies of writings by Womonwriters (conference attendees), conference chronological files, meeting notes, and membership lists. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
RESTRICTIONS: Membership mailings lists, in Box 3, are CLOSED until 2020.
Related Materials
Southern Lesbian-Feminist Activist Herstory Project
Lesbian authors -- Correspondence; Women authors; Lesbians -- Meetings; Lesbian authors; Lesbians' writings, American -- Publishing; Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture; Womonwrites
- Womonwrites Records, 1979-2009, 3 boxes
  Conditions Governing Access note
  CLOSED: The membership mailings lists in Box 3 are closed until 2020.
  - Womonwrites Anthologies, 1993-2009, 8 folders (Box 1)
  - Womonwrites Conferences, 1979-1996, 18 folders (Box 1)
  - Womonwrites Conferences, 1996- (Box 2)
  - Womonwrites Conferences (Box 3)
  - Meeting notes, undated (Box 3)
  - Organizational Mailing Lists, undated (Box 3)
  - Confidential Mailing Lists (Box 3)
    RESTRICTED
  - Womonwrites Conferences, 2010-2014 (Box 4)
  - Womonwrites Anthologies, 1986, 2012-2014 (Box 4)